<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Indicator on HumanitaRian useR Group</title>
    <link>/categories/indicator/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Indicator on HumanitaRian useR Group</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© This post is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License，please give source if you wish to quote or reproduce.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/indicator/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Profile of preference: Rashtree analysis</title>
      <link>/post/profile-of-preference/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/profile-of-preference/</guid>
      <description>Often affected population or key informant are requested to share their preference for specific type of interventions. How can we identify patterns of preference within a dataset? Can we identify groupings on the basis of several (categorical or continuous) variables that differentiate profiles optimally.
 This tutorial is based on the publication Priorities and preferences in humanitarian needs assessments -Their measurement by rating and ranking methods.
Loading packages ## This function will retrieve the packae if they are not yet installed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Estimation of sectoral priorities: Borda Count &amp; Plackett-Luce model</title>
      <link>/post/plackett-luce/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/plackett-luce/</guid>
      <description>Ratings and rankings account for the majority of data generated in the course of rapid key informant needs assessments during humanitarian emergencies. Using this information to develop consolidated need prioritisation comes with challenges. 
Practically speaking, the method presented here can be used for dataset that includes questions such as
 what’s your first need? (select_one among different options)
  what’s your second need? (select_one among different options)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Severity Index with R</title>
      <link>/post/compositeindicator/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/compositeindicator/</guid>
      <description>In this tutorial, We will see how to build a severity index using a key informant interview dataset. Building such index, also called composite indicator, is among the regular and expected task of any humanitarian data analyst.The objective is to summarize information into a simple indicator that can reduce information overflow. Severity index informs the sectoral and inter-sectoral discussions taking place as part of the Humanitarian Needs Overview (HNO) process, in particular facilitating a comparison of needs across geographic areas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How-to: Access ActivityInfo data with R</title>
      <link>/post/activityinfoscript/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/activityinfoscript/</guid>
      <description>ActivityInfo is a data collection and management platform used in the humanitarian sector, designed particularly for Monitoring &amp;amp; Evaluation. This short tutorial aims to explain how to access data using the ActivityInfo API with R. 
ActivityInfo version used for this tutorial is V4.0, focusing on the new interface (forms, not activities).
The activityinfo-R package “Be Data Driven”, the company managing ActivityInfo, has developed the “activityinfo-R” package. The package conveniently allows R users to read and write data through the ActivityInfo API.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>