<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data on HumanitaRian useR group</title>
    <link>/categories/data/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data on HumanitaRian useR group</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>© This post is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License，please give source if you wish to quote or reproduce.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/data/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Refugee Population Data Visualisation</title>
      <link>/post/refugee-population-viz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/refugee-population-viz/</guid>
      <description>UNHCR Population Statistics Database contains data about UNHCR’s populations of concern from the year 1951 up to 2014 as well as their general composition by location of residence or origin, their status, their evolution over time.
 Displacement Statistics The Population Database UNHCR’s populations of concern status includes:
 Refugees include individuals recognised under the 1951 Convention relating to the Status of Refugees; its 1967 Protocol; the 1969 OAU Convention Governing the Specific Aspects of Refugee Problems in Africa; those recognised in accordance with the UNHCR Statute; individuals granted complementary forms of protection; or those enjoying temporary protection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rhdx: a R package to interact with HDX</title>
      <link>/post/rhdx_demo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/rhdx_demo/</guid>
      <description>rhdx is an R package to interact with the HDX API.
It provide a series of utilities to facilitates interaction &amp;amp; analysis.
The Humanitarian Data Exchange (HDX) is an open platform for sharing data across crises and organisations. Launched in July 2014, the goal of HDX is to make humanitarian data easy to find and use for analysis. Our growing collection of datasets has been accessed by users in over 200 countries and territories.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accessing data from REST API using R: examples for KoBoToolbox and Country Based Pooled Fund (CBPF) data</title>
      <link>/post/kobo_restapi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/kobo_restapi/</guid>
      <description>R program has become a language of choice for data science work. It has rich feature library that can be readily used for variety of data management tasks. This article focuses on accessing data from the KoBoToolbox.
KoBoToolbox KoBoToolbox provides a suite of tools for field data collection in the challenging environments. It is free and open source and works both on and offline.
KoBoToolbox has a number of advanced features which are very useful for advanced use case scenario.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Humanitarian Data Scientist Job</title>
      <link>/post/humanitarian-data-scientist/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/humanitarian-data-scientist/</guid>
      <description>We have all heard and seen the trend of increasing volumes of data becoming available to us through a variety of mechanisms. With this trend, we have also seen the increased recognition of those who know how to handle such data. Historically, we may have referred to them as statisticians. However, as technologies in this discipline have multiplied and become affordable (or free), increasing numbers of people have been empowered to enter the business.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>