<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Animation on HumanitaRian useR group</title>
    <link>/categories/animation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Animation on HumanitaRian useR group</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>© This post is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License，please give source if you wish to quote or reproduce.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/animation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Euler chart for multichoice questions from Kobo</title>
      <link>/post/eulerkobo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/eulerkobo/</guid>
      <description>Multiple choice question in which respondent can select more than one correct answer from the list is a usual part of almost every survey.
It is usually visualized as a simple bar chart ignoring the overlap between the different categories, while this overlap can bring more analytical value and depth to the analysis.
Euler diagram is a perfect way to show the relationship between different subsets and that’s hardly possible to build it with the commonly used spreadsheet software such as MS Excel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bar Chart Race for Refugees</title>
      <link>/post/refugee-bar-chart-race/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/refugee-bar-chart-race/</guid>
      <description>“Bar Chart Race” are a specific type of bar chart that moves to show rankings over time. It became recently a quite popular approach to bring a storytelling elements within a longitudinal dataset. Readers are suggested to connect and combine what they see on the chart with other qualitive elements that they know about (elements of history). By using the allegory of F1 Race, it gives a very dynamic dimension.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fatal events in the Sahel</title>
      <link>/post/sahel-fatalities/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/sahel-fatalities/</guid>
      <description>In this short post (crossposted here), we will show how to use the rhdx, dplyr, purrr, sf and gganimate R packages to show the number of fatal incidents in 5 Sahelian countries. The rhdx package is not yet on CRAN, so you will need to use the remotes package to install it first:
remotes::install_gitlab(&amp;quot;dickoa/rhxl&amp;quot;) ## rhdx dependency remotes::install_gitlab(&amp;quot;dickoa/rhdx&amp;quot;) ## github mirror also avalailable install.packages(&amp;quot;gifski&amp;quot;) This analysis was inspired by this tweet by José Luengo-Cabrera, researcher at the Crisis Group.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>